<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<!-- This template is for creating an Internet Draft using xml2rfc,
     which is available here: http://xml.resource.org. -->
<!DOCTYPE rfc SYSTEM "rfc2629.dtd" [
<!-- One method to get references from the online citation libraries.
     There has to be one entity for each item to be referenced. 
     An alternate method (rfc include) is described in the references. -->
]>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='rfc2629.xslt' ?>
<!-- used by XSLT processors -->
<!-- For a complete list and description of processing instructions (PIs), 
     please see http://xml.resource.org/authoring/README.html. -->
<!-- Below are generally applicable Processing Instructions (PIs) that most I-Ds might want to use.
     (Here they are set differently than their defaults in xml2rfc v1.32) -->
<?rfc strict="yes" ?>
<!-- give errors regarding ID-nits and DTD validation -->
<!-- control the table of contents (ToC) -->
<?rfc toc="yes"?>
<!-- generate a ToC -->
<?rfc tocdepth="4"?>
<!-- the number of levels of subsections in ToC. default: 3 -->
<!-- control references -->
<?rfc symrefs="yes"?>
<!-- use symbolic references tags, i.e, [RFC2119] instead of [1] -->
<?rfc sortrefs="yes" ?>
<!-- sort the reference entries alphabetically -->
<!-- control vertical white space 
     (using these PIs as follows is recommended by the RFC Editor) -->
<?rfc compact="yes" ?>
<!-- do not start each main section on a new page -->
<?rfc subcompact="no" ?>
<!-- keep one blank line between list items -->
<!-- end of list of popular I-D processing instructions -->
<rfc category="info" docName="draft-reddy-dnsop-error-page-00"
     ipr="trust200902">
  <front>
    <title abbrev="DNS access denied error page">DNS Access Denied Error
    page</title>

    <author fullname="Tirumaleswar Reddy" initials="T." surname="Reddy">
      <organization abbrev="McAfee">McAfee, Inc.</organization>

      <address>
        <postal>
          <street>Embassy Golf Link Business Park</street>

          <city>Bangalore</city>

          <region>Karnataka</region>

          <code>560071</code>

          <country>India</country>
        </postal>

        <email>kondtir@gmail.com</email>
      </address>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Neil Cook" initials="N." surname="Cook">
      <organization>Open-Xchange</organization>

      <address>
        <postal>
          <street></street>

          <country>UK</country>
        </postal>

        <email>neil.cook@noware.co.uk</email>
      </address>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Mohamed Boucadair" initials="M." surname="Boucadair">
      <organization>Orange</organization>

      <address>
        <postal>
          <street></street>

          <city>Rennes</city>

          <code>35000</code>

          <country>France</country>
        </postal>

        <email>mohamed.boucadair@orange.com</email>
      </address>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Dan Wing" initials="D." surname="Wing">
      <organization abbrev="Citrix">Citrix Systems, Inc.</organization>

      <address>
        <postal>
          <street></street>

          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>

        <email>dwing-ietf@fuggles.com</email>
      </address>
    </author>

    <date />

    <workgroup>ADD</workgroup>

    <abstract>
      <t>This document defines an method to return a URL that provides
      additional information about the cause of blocking access to a
      domain.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>

  <middle>
    <section anchor="intro" title="Introduction">
      <t>There are many reasons that a DNS query may be blocked, the following
      discusses some of the reasons:</t>

      <t><list style="symbols">
          <t>Various network security services are provided by Enterprise
          networks to protect endpoints (e.g,. Hosts, IoT devices).
          Network-based security solutions such as firewalls (FW) and
          Intrusion Prevention Systems (IPS) rely on network traffic
          inspection to implement perimeter-based security policies. The
          network security services may for example prevent malware download,
          block known malicious URLs, block phishing sites etc. These network
          security services act on DNS requests originating from
          endpoints.</t>

          <t>Network devices in a home network offer network security to
          protect the devices connected to the home network by performing
          DNS-based content filtering. The network security service may for
          example block access to domains to enforce parental control, block
          access to malware sites etc.</t>

          <t>ISPs typically block access to access to domains is due to an
          external requirement imposed by an external entity (e.g., Law
          Enforcement Agency) by performing DNS-based content filtering.</t>
        </list></t>

      <t>The typical mechanisms to block a DNS query and their limitations are
      illustrated below:<list style="symbols">
          <t>The DNS response is forged providing IP addresses that points to
          a HTTP(S) server alerting the end user of the reason for blocking
          access to the domain (e.g., malware). The extended error code
          "Forged answer" defined in <xref
          target="I-D.ietf-dnsop-extended-error"></xref> can be used by the
          client to identify the DNS response the forged. When a HTTP(S)
          enabled domain is blocked, the network security device presents a
          block page instead of the HTTP response from the content provider.
          If a HTTP enabled domain is blocked, the network security device
          intercepts the HTTP request and returns a block page over HTTP. If a
          HTTPS enabled domain is blocked, the block page is also served over
          HTTPS. In order to return a block page over HTTPS, MITM is enabled
          on endpoints by generating a local root certificate and an
          accompanying (local) public/private key pair. The local root
          certificate is installed on the endpoint, and the network security
          device(s) store a copy of the private key. During the TLS handshake,
          the network security device modifies the certificate provided by the
          server and (re)signs it with the private key from the local root
          certificate. However, configuring the local root certificate on
          endpoints is not viable option in several deployments like Home
          networks, Schools, Small Office/Home Office (SOHO) and Small/ Medium
          Enterprise (SME). Further, Enterprise networks do not assume that
          all devices in their network are managed by the IT team or Mobile
          Device Management (MDM) devices, especially in the quite common BYOD
          ("Bring Your Own Device") scenario. The local root certificate
          cannot be installed on IoT devices without a device management tool.
          In this case, the browser will encounter HTTPS certificate error
          when the browser is redirected via DNS to a web page hosted to
          display the block page. An end user therefore does not know why the
          connection was reset and, consequently, may repeatedly try to
          unsuccessfully reach the domain. Frustrated, the end user may use
          insecure interfaces to reach the domain, potentially compromising
          both security and privacy. Furthermore, certificate errors train
          users to click through certificate errors, which is poor security
          practice. To eliminate the need for an end user to click through
          certificate errors, an end user may install a local root certificate
          on a host device. Doing so, however, is also poor security practice
          as it creates a security vulnerability that may be exploited by a
          man-in-the-middle attack.</t>

          <t>The DNS response is forged to provide a NXDOMAIN response to
          cause the DNS lookup to terminate in failure. In this case, an end
          user does not know why the domain cannot be reached, and may
          repeatedly try to unsuccessfully reach the domain. Frustrated, the
          end user may use insecure interfaces to reach the domain,
          potentially compromising both security and privacy.</t>

          <t>The extended error codes Blocked, Censored and Filtered defined
          in <xref target="I-D.ietf-dnsop-extended-error"></xref> can be
          returned by the DNS server to provide additional information about
          the cause of an DNS error. These extended error codes does not
          suffer from the above limitations but the user still does not know
          the exact reason or is aware of the exact entity blocking the access
          to the domain. For example, a DNS server may block access domain
          based on the content category like "Adult Content" to enforce
          parental control, "Violence &amp; Terrorism" due to an external
          requirement imposed by an external entity (e.g., Law Enforcement
          Agency) etc. The content categories for domains cannot be
          standardized because the classification of domains into content
          categories is vendor specific, typically ranges from 40 to 100 type
          of categories depending on the vendor and the categories keep
          evolving. Further, the threat data used to categorize domains may
          seldom mis-classify domains (e.g., Domains wrongly classified as DGA
          (Domain generation algorithm) by deep learning technique, domain
          wrongly classified as phishing due to crowd souring, new domains not
          categorized by the threat data). The end user needs to know the
          contact details of the IT/InfoSec team to raise a complaint.</t>
        </list></t>

      <t>This document focuses on addressing the above limitations by defining
      an method to return a URL that provides additional information about the
      cause of blocking access to a domain.</t>
    </section>

    <section anchor="notation" title="Terminology">
      <t>The key words "MUST", "MUST NOT", "REQUIRED", "SHALL", "SHALL NOT",
      "SHOULD", "SHOULD NOT", "RECOMMENDED", "NOT RECOMMENDED", "MAY", and
      "OPTIONAL" in this document are to be interpreted as described in BCP 14
      <xref target="RFC2119"></xref><xref target="RFC8174"></xref> when, and
      only when, they appear in all capitals, as shown here.</t>

      <t>This document makes use of the terms defined in <xref
      target="RFC8499"></xref> and <xref
      target="I-D.ietf-dnsop-terminology-ter"></xref>.</t>

      <t>'DoH/DoT' refers to DNS-over-HTTPS and/or DNS-over-TLS.</t>
    </section>

    <section title="Method to return the URI">
      <t>TBD: TXT record or a new RRType or SVCB records.</t>
    </section>

    <section title="ERROR Page ">
      <t>The following section outlines the recommended contents of a error
      page.</t>

      <t>TODO</t>
    </section>

    <section title="Usability considerations">
      <t>If the error page is displayed in a language not known to the end
      user, browser extension to translate the language can be used by the
      user. For example, "Google Translate" extension <xref
      target="Chrome-Translate"></xref> provided by Google on Chrome can be
      used by the user to translate the error page. The "Google Translate"
      extension automatically detects if the language of a page is different
      from the language the user has selected. If it is in a different
      language, a banner appears at the top of the page. The user can click on
      the Translate button in the banner to have all the text on the page
      appear in the language selected by the user. </t>
    </section>

    <section anchor="Security" title="Security Considerations">
      <t>Unless the DNS response that conveys the URL that provides additional
      information about the cause of blocking access to a domain is sent over
      DNS-over-HTTPS (DoH) <xref target="RFC8484"></xref> or DNS-over-TLS
      (DoT) <xref target="RFC7858"></xref>., the response is susceptible to
      forgery. DNS stub resolver MUST NOT fetch the URL unless DNS messages
      are exchanged over DoT/DoH. Bad actors can host DNS-over-TLS and
      DNS-over-HTTPS servers, and claim the servers offer privacy and
      filtering capability to block malware domains but exactly do the
      opposite to invade the security and privacy of the end user. This attack
      can be mitigated if and only if the endpoint selects DoT/DoH servers
      hosted by well-known organizations (e.g., ISPs, organization for which a
      user works etc.) or DoT/DoH servers pre-configured in the OS/Browser
      with filtering capability. The DNS client can learn the filtering
      capability of the DoH/DoT server using <xref
      target="I-D.reddy-add-server-policy-selection"></xref>. It also
      discusses how a DNS client can authenticate it is connecting to a
      DoH/DoT server hosted by a specific organization (e.g., ISP). This
      information is cryptographically signed to attest its authenticity. It
      is particularly useful when the DoH/DoT server is insecurely discovered
      and prevents the client from connecting to an attackers DoH/DoT
      server.</t>

      <t>The URL providing additional information about the cause of blocking
      access to a domain MUST only serve static content to limit the risk of
      security threats from dynamic content (e.g., malicious JavaScript). The
      error page MUST comply with the recommended contents of a error page
      defined in Section 4. The endpoint can use deep learning techniques to
      analyze the error page for compliance.</t>
    </section>

    <section anchor="IANA" title="IANA Considerations">
      <t>This document has no actions for IANA.</t>
    </section>

    <section title="Acknowledgements">
      <t>TODO.</t>
    </section>
  </middle>

  <!--  *****BACK MATTER ***** -->

  <back>
    <references title="Normative References">
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.2119'?>

      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.8174'?>

      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.8484'?>

      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.7858'?>

      <?rfc include='reference.I-D.ietf-dnsop-extended-error' ?>
    </references>

    <references title="Informative References">
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.8499'?>

      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.8598'?>

      <?rfc include='reference.I-D.reddy-add-server-policy-selection'?>

      <?rfc include='reference.I-D.ietf-dnsop-terminology-ter'?>

      <reference anchor="Chrome-Translate"
                 target="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/google-translate/aapbdbdomjkkjkaonfhkkikfgjllcleb/RK%3D2/RS%3DBBFW_pnWkPY0xPMYsAZI5xOgQEE-">
        <front>
          <title>Google Translate</title>

          <author></author>

          <date day="" month="" year="" />
        </front>
      </reference>

      <!---->
    </references>
  </back>
</rfc>
